http://www.greenvillewomensclinic.com/privacy-policy

Greenville Women's Clinic
Home
Abortion Pill (RU486)
PRIVACY POLICY
EFFECTIVE DATE: 5/2018NOTICE OF PRIVACY PRACTICES FOR PROTECTED HEALTH INFORMATIONThis notice describes how medical information about you may be used and disclosed and how you can get access to this information. PLEASE READ IT CAREFULLY.Greenville Women's Clinic and staff are committed to protection the privacy of your health record and the confidentiality of your visit. In accordance with the Federal Health Information Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA), our commitment to your privacy EXCEEDS the requirements of the law.Your healthcare record, known as a chart, and the information it contains will not be disclosed or released to any one outside this office without your written authorization except as allowed by state or federal law.NO ONE, including your parent or spouse, will be allowed access to your information without your written authorization except when required by law. Whenever possible, the information will be “de-identified,” that means your name, address, and other identifying information will be removed.Greenville Women's Clinic will use your health information for the purpose of:TreatmentFor example, information obtained by us will be used by staff members to determine the best treatment for you. When you choose to give us personal information, we keep it confidential, and solely for scheduling your requested appointment.PaymentIf you want to submit a claim to your insurance company for reimbursement, we will assist you in preparing the necessary forms. Most insurance companies do NOT pay for our services, but every company is different and some may pay in special circumstances.Regular Healthcare OperationsFor example, members of our staff may use some information in your chart to assess the care you received and the outcomes for the purpose of our Continuous Quality Improvement Program.Business AssociatesGreenville Women's Clinic may share information with our insurance company in response to litigation. De-identified statistical information may be released to the National Abortion Federation (NAF)
and other organizations to improve the quality of our care. Any outside agency will also be required to safeguard your information.Disclosures Required by Law:United States Government Greenville Women's Clinic may be required by law to report health information related to adverse events with regard to defective products to the Food and Drug Administration (FDA), the Centers for Disease Control (CDC) or the Health and Human Services Administration (HHS).State of South CarolinaThe State requires reporting of statistical information regarding abortions, including age, race, marital status, and city of residence. We WILL NOT release your name, address, or any identifying information.Public HealthGreenville Women's Clinic may be required by law to report health information related to preventing certain communicable diseases, injury or disability.Law EnforcementGreenville Women's Clinic may be required to report health information in response to a valid subpoena such as in cases of abuse or other crimes.We do not sell, rent, share, or otherwise disclose mailing lists or other personally identifiable information. We maintain medical records of former patients should you need to contact us in the future.File a complaint if you feel your rights are violatedYou can complain if you feel we have violated your rights by contacting Greenville Women's Clinic at (864) 232-1584 and requesting to speak with the HIPAA Privacy Officer.If you feel we have been unable to provide satisfactory resolution, you can file a complaint with the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services Office for Civil Rights by sending a letter to 200 Independence Avenue, S.W., Washington, D.C. 20201, calling 1-877-696-6775, or visiting www.hhs.gov/ocr/privacy/hipaa/complaints/.We will not retaliate against you for filing a complaint.Changes to the Terms of this NoticeWe can change the terms of this privacy policy, and the changes will apply to all information we have about you. The new notice will be available upon request, in our office, and on our website.
Follow Us
1142 Grove Rd, Greenville, SC 29605  |  (864) 232-1584  | privacy policy© 2007-2019 Greenville Women's Clinic  All rights reserved.
Share by:
